Johnny Z. Song

From Centennial College

Phone: (647)896-5201

Email: johnny-zsong@outlook.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/johnny-zsong

January 4th, 2022

Re: Co-op job opportunities

Dear Human Resources,

addition to your team.

It is with great interest that I submit this cover letter and resumé to apply for the exciting opportunity in the four-month Co-op positions with Canadian Tire. As a methodical professional with a background of both medical science and IT technologies, I bring with me strong critical thinking skills, a technical aptitude, and passion for learning. I am currently a software engineering student specializing in Health Informatics Technology (Advanced Diploma) from Centennial College, and combined with my professional experience, I am confident that I will be a valuable

With a unique background, I have an ethos and curiosity for continuous professional development. My current pursuits of software engineering have given me the foundational skills in a portfolio of skills and experiences of IT technical specialist, including software system design and testing, web and mobile application development, database management as well as a suite of utility apps such as Microsoft 365 and Adobe, and ultimately solid industrial experience of Agile methodologies during my previous two Co-op terms with the Information Technology Team of CAAT Pension Plan where I learned much from real-world practice.

Based on the fruitful Co-op experience previously, I am keen on devoting myself to more challenges in the upcoming term so I can keep on proceeding along the path of a proficient IT technologist. Canadian Tire, a highly reputated retail giant, is undoubtedly an ideal workplace to offer ample resources that can help me grow.

I would welcome the opportunity to attend an interview to discuss my qualifications for this position. Thank you for your time and consideration.

Sincerely,

Johnny Z. Song

Johnny Z. Song

From Centennial College

Phone: (647)896-5201

Email: johnny-zsong@outlook.com

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/johnny-zsong

Entry-level Software Developer / Engineer

Programmer I DevOps I UX/UI Design I Data Analyst I Technical Specialist

HIGHLIGHT OF SKILLS

C# / .NET 6

HTML5 / CSS / ES6

Vue.js / React.js

Linux & Docker

Git / GitHub / Azure DevOps

OracleDB/MongoDB

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer | Co-op @ CAAT Pension Plan (Canada)

May 2022 - Dec 2022 (8 months)

- Learned how to code using ASP.NET Core and Vue.js.
- Created unit tests for the backend project and lifted code coverage by about 10%.
- Optimized CI pipelines in Microsoft Azure DevOps to improve the outcomes of automated testing.
- Composed technical documents on UI branding, frontend validations, error handling and messaging to help newcomers and non-technical professionals to understand the team projects

Skills: C# · ASP.NET Core · Vue.js · xUnit · Git /Azure DevOps · CI/CD · Agile Methodology and Practice

Manager of the Blood Typing Reference Laboratory @ Guizhou Blood Center (China)

Dec 2017 - May 2021

- Promoted the use of cloud-based lab inventory management systems
- Developed an experiment log and report system using VBA for Excel to optimize daily workflow
- Founded a library of rare blood types for local blood donors based on NGS techniques
- Revised SOP to update experiment protocols, standards and procedures for improved outcome and safety

Clinical Laboratory Technologist @ Guizhou Blood Center (China)

June 2015 - May 2021

- Performed immunohematology-based assays for red blood cell and platelet typing
- Responsible for new employee training and instrument maintenance

Skills: Laboratory Skills · Immunology · Immunohematology · Molecular Biology · VBA for Microsoft 365

Academic Administrator @ Guizhou Medical University (China)

Sept 2011 - June 2015

- Managed student performances, transcripts and graduation auditting
- Designed keynotes for the principals and department leaders in various projects
- Carried out advisory work for students of the Foreign Language Institution

Lecturer of Immunology and Transfusion Medicine @ Guizhou Medical University (China)

Sept 2012 - June 2014, Aug 2017 - Jan 2021

- Provided instruction, lab-based coaching, feedback, and academic assessments
- Instructed and supported students with academic and lab-based research projects

Skills: Communication · Adobe · Microsoft 365 · Medical Education · Immunology Immunohematology · Molecular Immunology

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Technology - Health Informatics (Advanced Diploma)

Sept 2020 - Present

Centennial College, Ontario, Canada

GPA: 4.1/4.5

Core Courses: Software Engineering & System Design, Software Testing & QA, Data Structure & Algorithms, Unix/Linux C# & Java Programming, Advanced Database Concepts, Web Application Development, Mobile Application Development

Immunology (Master of Science)

Guizhou Medical University, Guizhou, China

Pharmacology (Bachelor of Science)

Central South University, Hunan, China

2002 - 2006



2008 - 2011